while you're preparing yourself mentally
to start your career search and you've
done the other things you've bought off
depression and and self-doubt and all
that know that it's never too late and
i' I've told several other stories about
people who have gotten late starts I I
mentioned people in their 60s I
mentioned people you know the woman who
was trying to make the change I just
talked about her in the previous video
about putting the time in um and there
are everybody constantly and if you're
the chat please speak up there are a lot
of people who have decided to change
their career there's a line in Bas
lurman sunscreen song where he says um
some of the most interesting
40-year-olds still don't know what they
want to be when they grow up um and this
would be true for me and I'm going to
share a story it's just how I operate
here from my own life um when I I
majored in Russian and let people want
to know how the hell did you end up with
you know a really solid Tech Career
and there's a lot of nuances to this and
I can go really deep into the whole
thing but it boiled down to my my wife
at the time saying she would never go
back to Russia and that meant that I had
to Res skill I just spend all the money
on on a college education I hope that
you can relate to this because there the
point is is that life changes um and you
know causes you to do different things I
have so many examples of this in my life
and there's one very this is one very
specific example I'm going to use it to
to lead into the other um topics as well
in the other videos when I couldn't do
Russian anymore I had to ask myself what
can I do is it too late for me to get a
tag career is it too late for me to um
you know to go back to some other some
other thing and the answer is it wasn't
too late and I was able to to make it
happen right and it's you're always able
to go put the time in if you're willing
to put the time in and you can always
always do it it's never too late you can
always change your stars um you can
think that it's too late for you and
because you're too old I I've had so
many people when I was at IBM tell me
that it was too late for them they were
just going to wait for retirement they
didn't they couldn't you know begin to
try to re-enter the workforce and it's
really never that dramatic um so I had
to I had to get a job doing something
else and I actually took
unemployment um because the the tech
company that I chose to work for the
startup went went under and um but
because I had had made that change and
taught myself uh it wasn't too late to
do that and then to to change again
later and I had several opportunities of
doing that so I just wanted to say that
it's just um it's just never too late it
really isn't it's never too late for you
to try that um and and I that's it